(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T22:00:20.255921",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
最初目合って 合って 合ってって
Our eyes met at first, matching, matching...
ゴロンゴロンてヤンヤン プリティプリティダイエットday
Rolling around, yay-yay, pretty pretty diet day
アイマイニー カーニバルに アイマイニー カーニバルに
Aimai-ni carnival, aimai-ni carnival
病み悪化してんだって 愛だ恋だ何だってんだ
They say sickness is worsening, love, romance, whatever
ざまあ見ろ 愛だって 愛だって 吐いたって
Serves you right, saying it's love, it's love...
投げたって ああ もう 何もない 何もないな
Throwing it away, ah, there's nothing, nothing left
寂しい寂しいノーセンスday
Lonely, lonely, no-sense day
精々まあ 愛だって 愛だって 吐いたんなげたって
At most, saying it's love, it's love, throwing it away...
もう何もない もう何もないな 寂しい寂しいノーセンスday
There's nothing left, nothing left, lonely, lonely no-sense day
いっそマイダーリンに 嘘のないダーリンに
Instead, to my darling, to a darling without lies
溺れ どれ おどれ 亡霊だ
Drown, slave, dance, dance, you're a ghost
何もない 何もない 私 何もない
There's nothing, nothing, I have nothing
ねえ 変われない 変われない 私 変われない
Hey, I can't change, can't change, I can't change
ねえ 分からない 分からない 分かる分からない
Hey, I don't get it, I don't get it, I get it, I don't get it
ねえもっと痛いこと隠して
Hey, hide something even more painful
だだだだダリダ ダーリン (笑)
Da-da-da-da dalida darling (lol)
はい 咎めない 愛情論 で おねだり
Yes, begging with an unblaming theory of love
だだだだダリダ ダーリン 脳内 汚 & 汚
Da-da-da-da dalida darling, brain dirty & dirty
会いたい衝動埋めてよ ダ ダ ダーリン
Fill the urge to see you, da-da-darling
ないない静寂感 女がひとり
Nai-nai, a sense of silence, a single woman
ないない純情感情 涙がひとり
Nai-nai, pure emotion, a single tear
ないない順序かさまし ダーリン
Nai-nai, padded order, darling
だだだだダリダ ダーリン 出会った 会えたって
Da-da-da-da dalida darling, meeting, being able to meet
まあね ゴロンゴロンて ヤンヤン 食い地 食い地 ダイエットday
Well, rolling around, yay-yay, greedy, greedy diet day
もっといっぱい ダーリン ぼろんおてがるに無利
Even more, darling, casually impossible
やみあかししてんだって しょにしょにせいたいだ
They say it's revealed, initial initial desire
ねぇ 走らない 走らない 私走らない
Hey, I won't run, won't run, I won't run
ねぇ 分からない 分からない 分かる分からない
Hey, I don't know, I don't know, I know, I don't know
一人手全部片足して
Counting everything with one hand and foot
ッタッタッタッたりたりたりたり
Ta-ta-ta-ta, ta-ri, ta-ri, ta-ri, ta-ri
マイナ愛蔵飲んで冷めたり
Drinking my minus favorite and cooling down
ッタッタッタッ折り畳み 足んないちょうど閉じてよ ッタッタッたり
Ta-ta-ta-ta, folding up, not enough, just close it, ta-ta-ri
踊れ 踊れ
Dance, dance,
叫べ 叫べ
shout, shout,
踊れ 踊れ ルーロッパパ ルーロッパパ
dance, dance, ro-ro-pa-pa, ro-ro-pa-pa,
踊れ 踊れ
dance, dance,
歌え 歌え
sing, sing,
踊れ 踊れ ルーロッパパ ルーロッパパ
dance, dance, ro-ro-pa-pa, ro-ro-pa-pa
もうドキドキの 心配ドキドキの 排出がおは全部無くして
My heart is pounding, worry is pounding, losing all emissions
ッタッタッタッたりたりたりたり
Ta-ta-ta-ta, ta-ri, ta-ri, ta-ri, ta-ri
どうしようもないから この身はあなたに
Since I have no choice, this body is yours
ッタッタッタッたりたりたりたり
Ta-ta-ta-ta, ta-ri, ta-ri, ta-ri, ta-ri
体調どうで埋めてよ ッタッタッたり
Fill it with how I feel, ta-ta-ri
あんなのそんなのんなのんなの なんなんなんなんのそのヘロをき
Like that, like this, nan-nan-nan-nan, who cares about that hero
たりしたり なんなんなんなんのんなの なんなんなんなんの
Tari shitari, nan-nan-nan-nan, who cares
何にもそこんしょ ッタッタッたり
Nothing there, ta-ta-ri
ないない瞬動感情 ッタッタッたり
No-no instantaneous emotion, ta-ta-ri
値上がりちゅう
Prices rising mid-way
はるか遠い遠い昔剥かれた首輪
In the far-off, distant past, a stripped-away collar
人が欲しい人が欲しいと叫ぶ 呪いの首輪
Crying "I want people, I want people," a cursed collar
怒らないで 見捨てないで どこもいかないで (ねぇ)
Don't get angry, don't abandon me, don't go anywhere (hey)
強く締める 吐くまで締める 人がいないいないと
Strangling tightly, until I throw up, when there is no one around
いい成績でしょ ねぇ ねぇ いい子でしょ
Good grades, right? Hey, hey, am I a good kid?
かわいい子でしょ ねぇ ねぇ 良い子でしょう 苦しい ねぇ
A cute kid, right? Hey, hey, a good child, it hurts, hey
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more
愛して 愛して 狂おしい ほど に
Love me, love me, to the point of madness
苦しい 苦しい 呪縛 を 解い て 解い て ねぇ 止められない ah
Painful, painful, break the binding spell, break it, ah, it can't be stopped
身体 身体 大きく なっても 小さい 首輪
Even as my body, my body grows, the collar remains small
苦しく なる 足りる なくなる 人 が 人 が 足りない
It gets painful, it's not enough, there aren't, there aren't enough people
クラスの 誰 にも 負け ない キレイ ない い 子 でしょう ( ねぇ )
I won't lose to anyone in class, aren't I a lovely, good kid? (Hey)
あの 子 より どの 子 より 誰も彼も私を見てよ
More than that kid, more than any other kid, everyone look at me
体育館裏 あなたに告白 嘘みたいでした
Behind the gymnasium, my confession to you seemed like a lie
あなた が 好きな の 汚い あなた が
I love you, you who are so filthy
愛して 愛して 愛して 全部あげる
Love me, love me, love me, I'll give you everything
あなたに あなたに 全部 背負っ て もらう よ
I'll have you, I'll have you shoulder everything
足りない あなた が 足りない 離さ ないで ah - ah ごめんなさい
It's not enough, you're not enough, don't let go, ah-ah, I'm sorry
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more
愛して 愛して 狂おしい ほど に
Love me, love me, to the point of madness
苦しい 離さない 苦しい もっともっと ねぇ 幸せ なのか ah, ah
It hurts, don't let go, it hurts, more and more, hey, is this happiness, ah, ah
幸せ なのか ah
Is this happiness, ah
愛して 愛して 愛して もっともっと
Love me, love me, love me, more and more
愛して 愛して 狂おしい ほど に
Love me, love me, to the point of madness
苦しい 離さない 苦しい あなたに 離さない
It hurts, don't let go, it hurts, to you, won't let go
幸せなの？
Is this happiness?
はーい、ということでー、
Hi there! So...
ちょっと待ってね。
Hold on a second.
え、夏色祭り誕生日ライブ、「夏色リスタート」開幕しましたー！いえーい！
Um, Natsuiro Matsuri's birthday live, "Natsuiro ReSTART" has officially started! Yay!
え、ダーリンだって、愛して愛して愛をしてお聴きいただきました。
Um, you've just heard "Darling Datte Aishite Aishite Aishite".
どうだった？どうだった？可愛かったでしょー？ねえ？クソ可愛かったでしょ？
How was it? How was it? Wasn't it cute? Right? Super cute, right?
この日のために可愛さをむっしゅむしゅにしてきました！
I made it super, super adorable just for this day!
えー、可愛い？ほらほらほらほら。
Ahem, cute? Look, look, look, look.
そして、なんとね、あの、もう気づいた方もいるかもしれないんですけど、
And what's more, um, some of you might have already noticed, but
祭すもね、頭の上にいますと可愛いでしょ。
Matsuri is also right up here on my head, isn't she cute?
誕生日だからね、一番近くでお祝いしてもらおうかなと思って特別席、特等席を
Since it's my birthday, I wanted her to celebrate right up close, so I made a special, front-row seat
作りましたよ。なんとね、
for her. And you know what?
どんぐりも食べれたりするみたい。どう？やっていける？できますか？
It looks like she can even eat acorns. How is it? Can you handle it? Can you?
そう、これ、めっちゃ可愛くない？ねえ、可愛いよねこれ。
Yeah, isn't this super cute? Hey, isn't it cute?
他にもね、なんか、わちゃわちゃつって、なんか、動けるみたいで。うん、可愛いでしょう？
Also, it looks like she can move around all lively and stuff. Yep, isn't she cute?
そう、めっちゃね、可愛いんですけど、まあ、祭りよりは、ちょっと負けてるかな？祭りのほうが可愛いみたいのとありますね。はい。
Yeah, she's super cute, but well, compared to Matsuri, maybe she loses a bit? Like, Matsuri is cuter, that kind of thing. Yes.
そして、そしてですね、ここからはなんと！豪華ゲストによるコラボパートなんですが、ちょっと一旦水を飲んでいいですか？いいですか？いただけます？はい、すみません。
And then, from here on, what's more! It's a collaboration part with gorgeous guests, but can I drink some water for a moment? Is that okay? May I? Yes, sorry.
はい。大丈夫です。
Yes. I'm okay.
ええ、コラボパートなんですけど、ハッシュタグ「夏色リスタート」でツイートしてたくさんたくさん盛り上げてほしいので、皆さん「夏色リスタート」ハッシュタグつけてツイートをお願いします。
Um, it's the collaboration part, but I want you to tweet with the hashtag "#NatsuiroReSTART" and hype it up lots, so everyone, please tweet with the hashtag.
はい、ということで、早速いきたいんですが、曲も噛んでるので、
Yes, with that said, I'd like to get right into it, but my pronunciation is stumbling over the song too,
最後までコメントたくさんして、まあ、祭りちゃん推しの人がほとんどだとは信じたいんですけど、まあ、他に推しがいる方はね、他の子も全力で愛してあげてください。
so please keep commenting a lot until the very end. I'd like to believe most of you are Matsuri-oshi, but for those with other oshi, please love the other girls with all your might too.
では、さっそくいきましょう！コラボパート、スタート！
Now then, let's go right into it! Collaboration part, start!
にっこり調査隊！お宅拝見！
Nikkori Survey Team! Inspecting your home!
今日も今日とて最高です！
Today is wonderful as always!
おーばんちゃい！
Oh, banhai!
コレクション、サンキュー！いいぞもっとやれ！
Collection, thank you! Nice, keep it up!
我々は世界一不幸を幸せにする
We are the ones turning the world's misery into happiness
世界一迷惑な、おせっかい調査隊だ！
The world's most annoying, meddling survey team!
100歩譲って、おせっかいにしてもだ！
Even if you grant us 100 steps, being meddling is—
無駄な御構いはお断りなんだが！？
We're declining unsolicited kindness!
とにかくあれだほら、頼み事はある意見にしか？
Anyway, look, do you have any requests or opinions?
順序が逆！今日もこのチェックを始めまーす！
Order is reversed! Today's check starts now!
まずは基本の「パ」パパパスポート持ってった？
First is the basic "Pa", Pa-Pa-Passport, did you bring it?
「キ」キキキ着替え忘れた？
"Ki", Ki-Ki-Ki-Change of clothes, did you forget?
「モ」モモモバイルバッテリー持った？
"Mo", Mo-Mo-Mobile battery, did you bring it?
「コ」ココ心臓は持った？もちろん！
"Ko", Ko-Ko-Heart, did you bring it? Of course!
仲間がいて、私がいる
With my comrades and me here,
時間も普通じゃない、誰のことかな？
time isn't normal either, whose business could it be?
僕らには不可能を可能に変える魔力があるさ！
We have the magic to turn the impossible into possible!
カリカリカリカリカリカリアンサー！あちらもこちらも千客万来！
Kari-kari-kari-kari-kari-kari-answer! Welcoming all guests near and far!
君の笑顔もコレクションにさせて！いえーい！
Let us add your smile to our collection too! Yay!
パパもママも関係なくて！これぞ一流のエンターテインメント！
Dads and moms alike, it doesn't matter! This is top-tier entertainment!
いつだっていつだっていつだっていつだって
Always, always, always, always,
いつか夢を叶えてやるって！ We can do it!
we'll make our dreams come true! We can do it!
ワクワクのパレードへようこそ！
Welcome to the exciting parade!
その笑顔をにっこりに変換！
Transform that smile into a big grin!
うちらにまかせて迷宮はスマイル！
Leave the maze to us, it's a smile!
上げのときだって 下げのときだって
Whether things are up or down,
かき混ぜちゃってスパイスだって！
Mix it all up with some spice!
完璧だね バリバリバリバリありかんだ
Perfect! Bari-bari-bari-bari...
おとなもこどもも ネスネスカンゲン
Adults and children alike, let's welcome!
もちろん我々も調査対象だ！
Of course, we're also investigation targets!
ナノウェイエイエイ！ いつか夢を叶えてやるって
Nanoway-ay-ay! Someday we'll make our dreams come true!
ウィキエンド！ みどりにふれてもっと胸を高鳴らせたっプ・リ・ス・ト・ン！
Weekend! Touching greenery makes our hearts race even more!
あ・い・う・え・おにぎり
A-I-U-E-Onigiri
あさから いっしょに おにぎり
Rice balls together from morning,
うちじゅう えがおで おにぎり
Smiles all over the house with rice balls,
こころも からだも ホカホカに なる
Heart and body become warm and cozy.
あ い う え おにぎり
A-I-U-E-Onigiri
きょうの おにぎり の なかみ は？
What is inside today's rice ball?
うめぼし に きめた！
Decided on pickled plum!
まっしろ ふっくら ちょっぴり しおあじ
Pure white, fluffy, slightly salted,
ぎゅっと にぎった その かたち たまらない
That tightly squeezed shape is irresistible!
あさから いっしょに おにぎり
Rice balls together from morning,
うちじゅう えがおで おにぎり
Smiles all over the house with rice balls,
こころも からだも ホカホカに なる
Heart and body become warm and cozy.
あ い う え おにぎり
A-I-U-E-Onigiri
きょうの おにぎり の なかみ は？
What is inside today's rice ball?
しゃけ に きめた！
Decided on salmon!
まっしろ ふっくら ちょっぴり しおあじ
Pure white, fluffy, slightly salted,
ぎゅっと にぎった その かたち たまらない
That tightly squeezed shape is irresistible!
あさから いっしょに おにぎり
Rice balls together from morning,
うちじゅう えがおで おにぎり
Smiles all over the house with rice balls,
こころも からだも ホカホカに なる
Heart and body become warm and cozy.
あ い う え おにぎり
A-I-U-E-Onigiri
きょうの おにぎり の なかみ は？
What is inside today's rice ball?
おかか に きめた！
Decided on bonito flakes!
まっしろ ふっくら ちょっぴり しおあじ
Pure white, fluffy, slightly salted,
ぎゅっと にぎった その かたち たまらない
That tightly squeezed shape is irresistible!
あさから いっしょに おにぎり
Rice balls together from morning,
うちじゅう えがおで おにぎり
Smiles all over the house with rice balls,
こころも からだも ホカホカに なる
Heart and body become warm and cozy.
神のまにまに
As the Gods Will
思い通りにいかないことだらけ
So many things don't go the way I want,
どうしようもなく自己嫌悪
Feeling hopelessly self-loathing,
八百万の痛みや悲しみから
From millions of pains and sorrows,
逃げ込める場所を探してる
Searching for a place to escape.
いっそ岩の隙間に引きこもって
I might as well hide in a rock crevice,
月も太陽も無視して眠ろう
And sleep, ignoring the moon and sun.
生まれてきた意味なんて知らない
I don't know the meaning of being born,
分かんないよ
I don't understand.
でもそんな風に思えるってこと それは
But the fact that you can think that way...
君がもっともっと素敵になれる力があるって教えてるんだよ
That tells you you have the power to shine brighter!
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに
That's right, just go with the flow,
誰だって地球を愛してる
Everyone loves this earth!
想い通りにいかないことばかり
Things never go the way I want,
どうしようもなく自己嫌悪
Leaving me with helpless self-loathing,
八百万の痛みや悲しみから
Escaping from millions of pains and sorrows,
逃げ込める場所を探してる
Searching for a place to hide.
いっそ岩の隙間に引きこもって
I might as well hide in a crevice of rocks,
月も太陽も無視して眠ろう
Ignoring the moon and sun to sleep.
まだまだ先は長いのさ
We still have a long way to go.
生まれてきたことの意味なんて
The meaning of having been born...
知らない 分かんないよ
I don't know, I don't get it.
でも そんな風に思えるってこと
But the fact that you can feel that way,
それは
That is...
君がもっともっと素敵になれる力が
Telling you that you have the power
あるって教えてんだろ
To become even more wonderful.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに
That's right, as God wills, as requested,
誰だって地球を愛してる
Everyone loves the Earth after all!
飲めや歌えや どんちゃん騒ぎ
Drink and sing, make a huge ruckus,
たまにはそんなのもいいね
That's fine once in a while too.
そうさ 北も南も 右も左も
That's right, north and south, right and left,
なんだかんだ地球を愛してる
Somehow or other, we all love the Earth.
泥んこだけど歩いて行ける
Even covered in mud, we can keep walking,
まだまだ先は長いのさ
We still have a long way to go.
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに
That's right, as God wills, as requested,
誰だって地球を愛してる
Everyone loves the Earth after all!
僕が笑って 君も笑えば
If I smile and you smile too,
許せないことなんてないよ
There's nothing that can't be forgiven.
そうさ 男も女も恋しかるべき
That's right, both men and women should love,
そんな風に地球は回ってる
That's how the Earth keeps spinning.
泥んこだけど歩いて行こう
Let's keep walking even if we're muddy,
まだまだ先は長いのさ
We still have a long way to go.
本当に大事なものなんて
Truly important things
数え切れないくらいの 中にあるよ
Are among the countless things we have.
先飲みの身の丈ばっか 爽快 裸踊りで 恥ずかしくない
Drinking ahead, dancing naked with joy—nothing to be ashamed of!
そうさ 神のまにまに 仰せのままに
That's right, as God wills, as requested,
もっともっと自分を愛せるよ
You can love yourself more and more.
鏡を見てごらんよ もう分かるでしょ
Take a look in the mirror, you'll understand.
みんなのお寺と 光り差す鳥居さ
Everyone's temple and the shining torii gate.
そうさ 神のまにまに みんなありがとう
That's right, as God wills, thank you everyone!
やっぱり地球を愛してる
After all, I truly love the Earth.
花を咲かせよう 大きな花を
Let's make flowers bloom, big flowers
天まで届くくらいの
That reach all the way to the heavens.
ラララ…
La, la, la...
Hey DJ かませ yeah, yeah, yeah
Hey DJ, let's drop it, yeah, yeah, yeah,
気分上々↑↑の
With spirits soaring high up,
針落とせ 音鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night!
飲もう ライライライ みんなで踊れ！
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー かけてよ ミラクル number
Hip-hop people, play that miracle number!
こんな時代に分かち合う music
Sharing our music in times like this,
探したくて回す地球儀
Spinning the globe in search of it.
グラつく不安定生活 それだからバランス重視
Faltering in unstable lives, balance is key.
良いことばかりじゃないから「頑張れる！」
It's not all good times, so we keep trying!
最悪な日にキック 再起動のボタンクリック！
Give that worst day a kick, click restart!
DJかけて！！ 今 trip
DJ, play it! Now take a trip.
シャレてるビートに乗って感じて体揺そうよ
Ride the stylish beat and rock your body!
Hey DJ かませ yeah, yeah, yeah
Hey DJ, let's drop it, yeah, yeah, yeah,
気分上々↑↑の
With spirits soaring high up,
針落とせ 音鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night!
飲もう ライライライ みんなで踊れ！
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
hip-pop ピーポー かけてよ ミラクル number
Hip-hop people, play that miracle number!
hip-pop アラビパンス デクロハソウ キップップ
Hip-hop, all the people, step across, keep up!
オリジナル探すキーポイント
The key point is searching for originality,
それぞれの色重ね合わせるレインボー
Overlapping each of our colors into a rainbow.
君に聞かせたいが為苦しむあがくの果て
After all the struggling to make you hear it,
十字固め 今を楽しみたいんだね
Cross-hold! You want to have fun right now.
let's hip-pop!! here we, here we go!!
はしゃぐフロアの上 頭中ゆさゆさぶる
Shaking our heads wildly on the excited floor!
Hey DJ ささやき うそさぼろう
Hey DJ, whisper and let's slack off.
Hey DJ かませ yeah, yeah, yeah
Hey DJ, let's drop it, yeah, yeah, yeah!
We got restart
もう一勝負 愛が今ある 絶好調
Another shot, love is here now, we're in top form!
We got restart
本気でRock you 夢のために
Rocking out for our dreams!
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて ここで 一発勝負
Taking it all in, bitter and sweet, this is our one-shot deal!
一世一代の大バクチ そんな中程で何? 大あくび
A once-in-a-lifetime gamble, what's with all the sighing?
締めるどこ締めな So ugly 行こうぜ 勝利の争奪に
Let's go for the win, ugly or not!
何が大事? I.MY.ME 失う前に 試合開始
What really matters? I.MY.ME. Don't lose it before the match begins!
これで最後 Restart これでわかる本物のSTAR
This is the very last Restart, this is where we find our true STAR!
夢を見る理由は 尽きせぬリアルな充実感
The reason we dream is a boundless sense of reality.
ひとつ叶えたところで 終わりじゃないでしょ?
Just because we made one wish come true doesn't mean it's over, right?
ミラーボール スモークこの匂い
Mirror ball, smoke, and this scent,
溶けるようなハーモニー
Melting into a harmonious rhythm.
身にまとって 踊りかすが
Dressed to the nines, dancing away,
無邪気なままで
Just living life raw and free.
We got restart
もう一勝負 愛が今ある 絶好調
Another shot, love is here now, we're in top form!
We got restart
本気でRock you 夢のために
Rocking out for our dreams!
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて ここで 一発勝負
Taking it all in, bitter and sweet, this is our one-shot deal!
サイコロは投げられた サイコロに賭けられた
The die has been cast, placed upon the dice,
御法度は「たられば」 イカサマ誰だ? インチキ おうちゃく は欺けないな
Who knows what's coming next? No cheating allowed!
後悔先立たず それでも役立たず
Don't regret it later or expect it to help you out.
今夜のおかず 有り付けたけりゃ まずは先立つ 夢の欠片差し出す
Just grab the pieces of our dreams right now!
何もしたくない 未来に期待もしていない
I didn't want anything, didn't expect a future,
そんな僕だった 君に出逢うまでは
Until I met you.
We got restart
今チャンス到来!! 勝利の女神よオーアイニー
Chance has arrived! Goddess of victory, oh yeah!
We got restart がっつりAlright
We got restart, all right!
愛があれば パッと一花咲かせてましょう
If we have love, let's make a flower bloom in a flash!
いくぜ 一点突破
Let's make our breakthrough!
We got restart
もう一勝負 愛が今ある 絶好調
Another shot, love is here now, we're in top form!
We got restart
本気でRock you 夢のために
Rocking out for our dreams!
We got restart 今チャンス到来!! 勝利の女神よオーアイニー
Chance has arrived! Goddess of victory, oh yeah!
We got restart がっつりAlright
We got restart, all right!
愛があれば パッと一花咲かせてましょう
If we have love, let's make a flower bloom in a flash!
いくぜ 一点突破
Let's make our breakthrough!
We got restart
もう一勝負 愛が今ある 絶好調
Another shot, love is here now, we're in top form!
We got restart
本気でRock you 夢のために
Rocking out for our dreams!
We got restart
もう一勝負 愛が今ある 絶好調
Another shot, love is here now, we're in top form!
We got restart
本気でRock you 夢のために
Rocking out for our dreams!
We got restart
もう一勝負 愛が今ある 絶好調
Another shot, love is here now, we're in top form!
We got restart
本気でRock you 夢のために
Rocking out for our dreams!
We got restart
もう一勝負 愛が今ある 絶好調
Another shot, love is here now, we're in top form!
We got restart
本気でRock you 夢のために
Rocking out for our dreams!
We got restart
もう一勝負 愛が今ある 絶好調
Another shot, love is here now, we're in top form!
i love mugic , i love you
I love MUGIC, I love you,
i need mugic …
I need MUGIC...
i love mugic , i love you
I love MUGIC, I love you,
i need mugic …
I need MUGIC...
i love mugic , i love you
I love MUGIC, I love you,
i love you
i need mugic …
I need MUGIC...
なんか最近元気ないん?
Hey, haven't you been looking down lately?
あんまり眠れてないみたいだし
It seems like you haven't been sleeping well.
友達だし隠し事ナシ! 話してごらんよ
We're friends with nothing to hide, so come talk to me!
だってテレビ見てもネットしても
I mean, even if you watch TV or browse the net,
つまらないニュースばか
There's only boring news to be seen.
それに宿題だってやらなきゃダメって溜め込んでばかり
And on top of that, homework we've procrastinated on too long!
そんなに拗ねてたって時間は過ぎていくから
If you sulk about it, time is just going to pass you by,
その指でその声を魔法を奏でてみようよ
So with that finger and that voice, let's play a magical melody!
誰の心の中にも眠る不思議なチカラ
Sleeping inside everyone's hearts is a strange, wonderful power.
くだらないことでもいいじゃない ありきたりなことでいいじゃない
It's fine if it's good for nothing, it's fine if it's ordinary!
君の心の中にも眠る素敵なチカラ
Sleeping in your heart is a beautiful, wonderful power.
それは“MUGIC”僕らを繋ぐ魔法の言葉
That is MUGIC, the magic word that connects us.
どうしてだろうこんなに近くに
I wonder why, even though she's so close that
手を伸ばせば届く距離なのに
If I stretched out my arm I'd be able to reach her.
ぁー俺のバカ! すれ違ってばか
Ah, I'm such an idiot! I just keep making mistakes.
気付けば顔も真っ赤っ赤
Before I knew it, my face was bright red.
確かにメールのやりとりじゃ
It's true that when conversing through emails,
うまく伝わらないことってあるよね
There are things that just don't get conveyed properly.
男ならそういうところはハッキリ言わなくちゃ
If you're a guy, you've got to say those things clearly!
一人で抱え込んだって何にも変わらないから
Holding it in by yourself isn't going to change a thing,
君の声と僕の声で奇跡を起こしてみようよ
So with your voice and my voice, let's try to start up a miracle!
誰の心の中にも眠る不思議なチカラ
Sleeping inside everyone's hearts is a strange, wonderful power.
頑張ってみればいいじゃない
It's fine if you just try your best,
疲れたら休めばいいじゃない
And if you're tired, it's fine to take a rest!
君の心の中にも眠る素敵なチカラ
Sleeping in your heart is a beautiful, wonderful power.
それは“MUGIC”僕らを繋ぐ魔法の絆
That is MUGIC, the magic word that brings us together.
10年後も100年後もずっとずっと先の未来も
Even 10 or 100 years from now, in the far future,
絶え間なく繰り返されるそれは言語も国も性別も越えて
This melody will keep echoing endlessly across the world,
名前も知らない顔も知らないまだ会ったこともない君のところへ
Reaching out to anyone—even someone we've never met.
届いてくこのメロディーが響いていくこの世界に誰の心の中にも眠る不思議なチカラ
Sleeping inside everyone's hearts is a strange, wonderful power.
君の心の中にも眠る素敵なチカラ誰の心の中にも眠る不思議なチカラくだらないことでもいいじゃない
It's fine if it's good for nothing, it's fine if it's ordinary!
ありきたりなことでいいじゃない君の心の中にも眠る素敵なチカラ
Sleeping in your heart is a beautiful, wonderful power.
それは“MUGIC”僕らを繋ぐ魔法の絆
That is MUGIC, the magic word that connects us.
Crossin' the star light night
Crossin' the starlight night
Crossin' the dreaming night
星のSite 未来と あなたと
At the star's site, with the future, with you,
もっと単純に だけど大胆に 「運命」recallして
more simply, yet boldly, recall "destiny".
Crossin' the star light night
Crossin' the starlight night
Kissin' the dreaming night
見つけないと ToNight あなたを
If I don't find you tonight,
デジタルメュの続きで遊ばせて
let me play in the digital dream's continuation.
世界で一つだけのi(愛)が始まる
The one and only love in the world begins.
受話器に映った誰かのアドレス
Someone's address reflected in the receiver.
瞳に呟く言葉が途切れる
The words whispered to your eyes trail off.
デタラメな時間を抜けて It's too fast
Breaking through the messy time, it's too fast.
探さないで波の扉の奥に鍵をかけて
Don't search for me, lock the door deep within the waves.
星の河で揺れて二人 出逢えたなら迷わないで
Swaying in the river of stars, if we met, don't hesitate.
Crossin' the star light night
Crossin' the starlight night
Crossin' the dreaming night
夢のSite 未来と あなたと
At the dream's site, with the future, with you,
ずっと曖昧で 今は本当に 「不可能」
always so ambiguous, right now truly "impossible".
Goodbye goodbye
Oh baby goodbye goodbye
No matter how many words we have to define
Goodbye goodbye
Oh darling goodnight goodnight
No matter how many times, it's just not right
Empty sky
I'm alone with no one nearby
But our memories ignite the passion that keeps us both alive
Invite us to the beautiful star sight...
好きになって！もっと！
Please fall in love with me more!
私を見て！もっと！
Please look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった 投げキスで”
My return for your support is "a kiss blown with all my love"!
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ ♡作って 恋しちゃって 下さい！
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting! Make a heart and fall in love!
やれる こと 何でも します
I will do whatever it takes!
NG なし で 体当たり 挑戦
A head-on challenge with no restrictions!
エゴサで 見つけた アンチの コメ
Finding anti-comments through ego-searching,
ふざけんな！…誰 より 分かってんし
don't mess with me!... though I understand it better than anyone.
でも 大丈夫 ステージに 立てば みんな が いる
But it's alright, as long as I stand on this stage, everyone is here!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Please fall in love with me more! Please look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった 投げキスで”
My return for your support is "a kiss blown with all my love"!
虜にする！もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll captivate you more! I'll show you more dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛 の こもった スペシャルナイト ファンサしちゃうぞ
Enjoy it to the fullest, a special night filled with love, I'll give you fan service!
お手紙 も 書いて ください！
Please write letters to me, too!
何度 も 読んで 宝物 に します
I'll read them over and over and make them my treasure.
スキャンダル まだ 早い けど
Scandals are still too early for me, but
裏切りません！ 宣言 します
I won't betray you! I declare it right here!
嫉妬、嫌がらせ に は 負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment.
ふざけんな！ 実力 で 勝って やる
Don't mess with me! I'll win with pure skill!
だから 辞めない 負けず嫌い 私 は いる
That's why I won't quit; I'm a sore loser, and I'm right here!
こぶし 上げて！もっと！汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fists higher! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは “ 愛 の こもった Monaビーム で ”
My return for your support is "with the Mona Beam filled with love"!
大歓声！もっと！まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
Give me louder cheers! More! Still not enough! Hey? More!
受け入れてね 愛 の こもった わがままソング ファンサしちゃうぞ
Please accept it, my selfish song filled with love, I'll give you fan service!
はぁ… 終わり が 近づく
Haa... The end is drawing near,
寂しい ね
how lonely.
楽しい の に 泣き そう だ よ
Even though I'm having fun, I feel like crying.
次 も 次 も また 会える よ ね？
We'll meet again next time, and the time after that, right?
優しさに 満ちている 言葉 も
Words overflowing with kindness,
心 ない 誰か の 言葉 さえも
even the heartless words from someone
必要 なん だ 必要 なん だ
are necessary, they are necessary.
強く なろう！
Let's become stronger!
好き に 叫べ！もっと！楽しんじゃえ！もっと！
Scream out your love! More! Enjoy it to the fullest! More!
忘れないで 特別 な 日 に なる よう に
Don't forget, hoping this becomes such a special day.
共に 歌おう ずっと！共に 歩め ずっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
合言葉 は とびっきり の L ・ O ・ V ・ E
Our secret word is the absolute best L-O-V-E!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Please fall in love with me more! Please look at me more!
恩返しは “愛のこもった 投げキスで”
My return for your support is "a kiss blown with all my love"!
虜にする！もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll captivate you more! I'll show you more dreams! More!
楽しんでって 愛 の こもった スペシャルナイト ファンサしちゃうぞ
Enjoy it to the fullest, a special night filled with love, I'll give you fan service!
はぁ… 終わり が 近づく...
Haa... The end is drawing near...
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”
I'll repay you with a kiss thrown with love!
気のせいじゃない 目は合っているよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting!
ハート作って恋しちゃってください！
Make a heart shape and fall in love with me!
やれること何でもします
I'll do whatever it takes,
NG無しで体当たり挑戦
Taking on challenges head-on with no restrictions!
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Anti comments I found on ego-surfing,
ぶざけんな！…誰より分かってるし
Don't mess with me! ...I know that better than anyone,
でも大丈夫ステージに立てばみんながいる
But it's okay, when I stand on this stage, everyone is here!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me more! Look at me more!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”(Fooo！！)
I'll repay you with a kiss thrown with love! (Fooo!!)
虜にする！もっと！夢を見せる！もっと！
I'll captivate you more! I'll show you dreams more!
楽しんでって 愛の込めたスペシャルナイト
Enjoy yourselves, a special night filled with love,
ファンサしちゃうぞ(・ω＜)
I'll give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them!
スキャンダルまだ早いけど
It's still too early for scandals,
裏切りません！宣言ときます
I won't betray you! I declare that right now!
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy and harassment!
ぶざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
Don't mess with me! I'll win with my real ability!
だから辞めない 負けず嫌い私はいる(行くよ！)
That's why I won't quit, I'm a sore loser, I am here! (Let's go!)
こぶし上げて！もっと！汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fists more! Sweat more!
恩返しは“愛の込めたmonaビームで”(Fooo！！)
I'll repay you with a mona beam filled with love! (Fooo!!)
大歓声！もっと！まだまだ！ねぇ？もっと！
Cheers more! More and more! Hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛の込めたわがままソング
Please receive my selfish song filled with love,
ファンサしちゃうぞ(・ω＜)
I'll give you fan service!
はーい、ということで
Hi everyone! So...
コラボパートからのまつりちゃんのファンサでいかがだったでしょうかー？
How was Matsuri's fan service after the collaboration part?
かんじなよー！いかがだったでしょうかー！
How was it?!
いや、めちゃめちゃ可愛かったよね。
Man, it was super cute, right?
みんなもね、あの、いっぱい協力してくれて嬉しかったでございます！
Thank you all so much for cooperating a lot, I'm so happy!
ということでみんなは気づいたことない？
So did you guys notice something?
これで気づかないやついたらちょっとあれですけども
If anyone didn't notice this, that'd be a bit...
どうよ？どうよ？この可愛い衣装！
How is it? How is it? This cute outfit!
そしてこの素晴らしい、素晴らしいこのステージ！
And this wonderful, wonderful stage!
今回の、えっと、ために、あ、これはですね
For this time, uh, this is,
100万人をチャンネル登録者数皆様のおかげで行きまして、そのね、記念として、まあ、ちょうど誕生日もちょうど良かったんでね、今回お披露目させていただきました！
Thanks to everyone reaching 1 million subscribers, and as a commemoration, and since my birthday was around the same time, we're unveiling it today!
どう？可愛いでしょう？これね、猫耳が
How is it? Isn't it cute? This, the cat ears...
このゲーミング、な、なんて言うんですか、ゲーミングヘッドホンみたいな感じになってるんですよ。
are like gaming, uh, what do you call it, gaming headphones!
これめっちゃ可愛いでしょ？ロゴもあったりして。そしてですね、この、なんたヘッドホンちょっと、と、と、取れ、取れ、取れる？取れる？
Isn't this super cute? It has logos too. And also, this, can these headphones come off?
お、ほらほらほら！そうするとね、このピアス！これホロライブのピアスをね、ちょっと作ってもらってつけております！
Oh, look look look! If you do that, these earrings! They made Hololive earrings for me, and I'm wearing them!
そしてそしてね、このお胸のところ行きますか？ちょっとセクシーな感じですが
And then, shall we check out the chest area? It's a bit sexy,
ここは取れませんけど、めちゃめちゃ可愛いでしょう？ベルトとかもして
you can't take this off, but isn't it super cute with the belt and all?
そしてスカート！これこだわりポイントです。このチラッと見えるね、太もも
And the skirt! This is a highlight. The thighs peeking out like this,
特に、いいでしょ？そしてね腰もね、めっちゃいいんです。この肉付きが
are especially nice, right? And the waist is also super nice. You can see the fleshiness,
わかりますか？プニット感。そう、これね、もしイラスト描いてくれる絵師様がいらっしゃったら
you know? That plump feeling. If there are any illustrators who want to draw fan art,
こだわってほしいですね。そしてね、あの、足！よくない？この厚底。超可愛くない？
please pay attention to that! And the legs! Aren't they great? These platform shoes. So cute!
そして一番こだわったポイント！こちら、ネイルしてるの！これね、まつりがデザインしたんですよ。
And the point I was most particular about! Look, I have nail art! Matsuri designed these.
めっかわでしょ？やばみじゃない？これ、あの、女性祭りすがいたらぜひお揃いにしてくだざい！
Super cute, right? Isn't it amazing? If there are any female fans, please match with me!
まずはこちらのヘッドホン、じゃなくて猫耳外せるんで、外してくるね。
First, these cat ears—well, not headphones, cat ears—can be removed, so let me take them off.
どう？どう？また印象違わない？可愛いでしょう？
How is it? Doesn't it give a totally different impression? Isn't it cute?
そしてそして、まだあるんですよ。なんとね、このスカートの周りについているジャケットっていうのか、なんて言うんだろ
And there's more! There's like a jacket or whatever you call it around the skirt...
んで、時間かかるかもだけど脱いでくるわ。
It might take a bit, but I'll go take it off.
えいしょ。この、結構ね、ベルトがね、
There. This... the belt's actually quite...
あの、忙しいんですよ。Hチチになるんでね。期待して
well, busy, you know? It gets pretty lewd, so look forward to it.
コメントたくさん打ってください。よろしくお願いしますね。
Please spam the chat with lots of comments! Thanks!
いやでもさ、この、何？背景っていうの？
But seriously, what's this? The background?
この場所もめちゃめちゃ良くない？景色いいよね！
Isn't this place amazing too? Great view!
景色良くてなんか近未来感もある感じになってて、めちゃめちゃまつりちゃんはすこでございますよ。
The scenery is nice and has a sci-fi feel, so Matsuri-chan is totally obsessed with it.
はいはいはい、めちゃ綺麗。これね、他のホロメンにも使ってほしいって思っているので、
Yeah, yeah, yeah, super pretty. I want other Holomem to use this too, so
使いたい方は、ぜひ、あの、ホロメンの中で使いたい方がいたらね、まつりちゃんに言わなくていいんで、スタッフさんに言ってください。
if any of the Holomem want to use it, you don't need to tell Matsuri-chan—just tell the staff.
お願いします！
Please!
ということで、お待たせしましたーー！
So, thanks for waiting!
どうどうどう？やばくないこれ？
Ta-da! Isn't this crazy?
これ、これヤバいでしょう！
This is insane, right?
めっちゃ、この斜めなんですよ、実はスカートがね。そう、
Look how slanted the skirt is, actually. Yeah,
で、太ももが結構見える。太もっていうかもうもはや
and you can see a lot of thigh. Thigh, or rather,
お尻なんじゃないかっていう、ホロライブサマーが帰ってきたレベルのエチチ加減でございますけども、
almost practically your butt—it's that kind of lewdness, on par with Hololive Summer returning, but...
ま、こんな感じでね、超絶可愛い祭りちゃんをお披露目したところで、
Well, with that super cute Matsuri-chan unveiled,
そろそろね、ラストスパートに行ってみようかと、思います。スクショもガンガン拡散してください。そして、
I think it's about time we head into the final stretch. Feel free to share screenshots everywhere! And also,
あの、ツイッターもね、ツイートたくさんしてくれると嬉しいので、ツイートもたくさんよろしくお願いします！
I'd be super happy if you tweeted a lot too, so please tweet lots!
ではではラストスパート行きますよー！
Now then, here we go into the final stretch!
では、続いての曲！カッコいい曲行っちゃいます！聞いてください！ラブカ！
Now, for the next song! We're doing a cool one! Listen up! "Loveka!"
ラブカ？
Loveka?
暗い 暗い 深海ベールに 包まれるわ ラ・ラブカ
Dark, dark, wrapped in a deep-sea veil, la-loveka.
奪い 奪い 叶わぬ願いは 打ち明けられず そのままが
Stealing, stealing, unfulfilled wishes remain unconfessed, just like that.
届け 届け それでも光は 水底 水面 その遥か
Reach, reach, yet the light is far beyond the ocean floor and surface.
暗い 暗い 未来の想いは 足らぬ 足らぬ 至らぬわ ラ・ラブカ
Dark, dark, thoughts of the future are not enough, not enough, not reaching, la-loveka.
ラ・ラブカ ラ・ラ・ラ・ラブカ
La-loveka, la-la-la-loveka.
あのキラビ ひろび ひろびるか それは バクバクバクバクか
That glittering, wide-open expanse, is it pounding?
嘘と 嘘に 染まった アイ・アイ・20か
Love, love, soaked in lies and lies, 20 or so?
サル・アイ・アイ・アイか 嗅ぎ出す 匂いか 届かぬ距離で 待っていた
Monkey-love, love, love? Sniffing out the scent? Waiting at an unbridgeable distance—
愛情は無い 猛攻はヤバい ラ・ラ・ラ・ラブカ
there's no affection. The onslaught is crazy, la-la-la-loveka.
暗い 暗い 深海ベールに 包まれるわ ラ・ラブカ
Dark, dark, wrapped in a deep-sea veil, la-loveka.
奪い 奪い 叶わぬ願いは 打ち明けられず そのままが
Stealing, stealing, unfulfilled wishes remain unconfessed, just like that.
届け 届け それでも光は 水底 水面 その遥か
Reach, reach, yet the light is far beyond the ocean floor and surface.
暗い 暗い 未来の想いは 足らぬ 足らぬ 至らぬわ ラ・ラブカ
Dark, dark, thoughts of the future are not enough, not enough, not reaching, la-loveka.
ラ・ラブカ ラ・ラ・ラ・ラブカ
La-loveka, la-la-la-loveka.
あのキラビ ひろび ひろびるか それは バクバクバクバクか
That glittering, wide-open expanse, is it pounding?
嘘と 嘘に 染まった アイ・アイ・20か
Love, love, soaked in lies and lies, 20 or so?
サル・アイ・アイ・アイか 嗅ぎ出す 匂いか 届かぬ距離で 待っていた
Monkey-love, love, love? Sniffing out the scent? Waiting at an unbridgeable distance—
愛情は無い 猛攻はヤバい
there's no affection. The onslaught is crazy.
クサる ラ・ラブカ 錆びたナイフに 落ちていた
Rotting away, la-loveka, fallen upon a rusted knife.
届く 距離で 出会って やり直すなら やめな
Meeting at a reachable distance—if you're gonna restart, don't.
僕らは 病まい ラ・ラ・ラ・ラブカ
We are sick, la-la-la-loveka.
ラ・ラブカ ラ・ラ・ラ・ラブカ
La-loveka, la-la-la-loveka.
本当の私
The real me...
知らないくせに
even though you don't know it,
分かったような 笑顔見せないで
don't look at me with that understanding smile.
近くにいても ずっと一緒でも
Even when we're close, even when we're always together,
理解もせずに 内心うざがって
without even understanding, feeling annoyed inside—
今日も無難に 過ごせるように
so I can get through today safely,
気づけばこんな 嫌な奴になってた
before I knew it, I had become such a hateful person.
本当の私を 愛してくれる人はいるのかな
Is there anyone who could love the real me?
ごめん いい子じゃなくて
Sorry for not being a good girl,
ずるくて だまして 壊れて 期待に応えられなくて
sneaky, deceitful, broken, and unable to meet expectations.
ごめん できそこないで 弱くて ださくて 腐って
Sorry for being a failure, weak, pathetic, rotting away—
燃えるは魅せられなくて
unable to show my burning passion,
それでも優しいのはなんで
yet why are you still so kind?
家族と家々 異なる命
Families and homes, different lives;
きっと全部は 分かり合えないよ
surely we can't understand everything.
嘘吐く私 演じる私
The me who lies, the me who acts—
誰が見たって 嫌な奴で最低だ
to anyone who sees, I'm a hateful, lowest person.
本当の私を知ったら きっと捨てられちゃうのかな
If you knew the real me, would you surely abandon me?
ごめん いい子じゃなくて
Sorry for not being a good girl,
寝反って 当たって 壊して
lashing out, striking, breaking things,
私で悩ませてしまって
causing you distress.
ごめん できそこないで 強がって 生きがって
Sorry for being a failure, acting tough, acting big,
もらった心を 汚してしまって それでも優しいのはなんで
tainting the heart you gave me—yet why are you still so kind?
胸晴れることは 今はないけれど できたら喜んでくれるかな
There's nothing I can be proud of right now, but if I could, would you be happy for me?
ああごめん 可愛くなくて
Ah, sorry for not being cute,
見た目も性格も嫌いで
hating my looks and personality
鏡も見たくないくらい 私に関わらないで
so much I don't even want to look in the mirror—please don't get involved with me.
話して 放って ぶつけて
Talking, letting go, clashing,
言ってはだめな言葉も
saying words I shouldn't—
それでも暖かいのはなんで
yet why are you still so warm?
ごめん いい子じゃなくて
Sorry for not being a good girl,
ずるくて だまして 壊れて 期待に応えられなくて
sneaky, deceitful, broken, failing to meet expectations.
ごめん できそこないで 弱くて
Sorry for being a failure, weak,
ださくて 腐って 燃えるは魅せられなくて
pathetic, rotting, unable to show my passion—
それでも優しいのはなんで
yet why are you still so kind?
胸張れること 今はまだないけれど できたら喜んでくれるかな
There's nothing I can be proud of just yet, but if I could, would you be happy for me?
ああごめん 可愛くなくて
Ah, sorry for not being cute,
見た目も性格も嫌いで
hating my looks and personality
鏡も見たくないくらい 私に関わらないで
so much I don't want to look in the mirror—please don't get involved with me.
話して 放って ぶつけて
Talking, letting go, clashing,
言ってはだめな言葉も
saying words I shouldn't—
それでも暖かいのはなんで
yet why are you still so warm?
ごめん いい子じゃなくて
Sorry for not being a good girl,
ずるくて だまして 壊れて
sneaky, deceitful, broken,
期待に応えられなくて
failing to meet expectations.
ごめん できそこないで 弱くて
Sorry for being a failure, weak,
ださくて 腐って
pathetic, rotting away—
萌ゆるは魅せられなくて それでも優しいのはなんで
unable to show my burning passion, yet why are you still so kind?
ごめん いい子じゃなくて
Sorry for not being a good girl,
どんな私も…
no matter what kind of me...
包んでくれる
Wrapping me in
とても大きな
a very big
愛はありました
love, it was there.
頑張って！追いかけて ほらもう少しだ
Do your best! Keep chasing, just a little more,
君と加速したら
if I accelerate with you,
もっとぎゅっと夢を抱きしめにいこう
let's go hold our dreams even tighter!
(せーのっ！)
(One, two!)
Yes！どんなときも
Yes! No matter the time,
Chance！あきらめない
Chance! I won't give up.
ほら (ほら) ほら (ほら)
Look (look) look (look),
夏色のココロが燃えてる
my summer-colored heart is burning!
アイアムミラクルオマツリガール！
I am a miracle omatsuri girl!
ほら (ほら) ほら (ほら)
Look (look) look (look),
誇しい自分になれるように
so I can become a proud version of myself!
なにくそ (ネバギバ)
No matter what (Never give up)
負けるか (ストーリー)
Will I lose? (Story)
すり減った靴底に明日が光るから
Tomorrow shines on my worn-out soles,
頑張って！追いかけて (Hi! Hi!)
Do your best! Keep chasing (Hi! Hi!)
もうちょっとなんだ (Fight! Fight!)
Just a little more (Fight! Fight!)
掴みたいトキメキ
The excitement I want to grasp.
勝手だって言われてもそれが私のポリシー
Even if they call me selfish, that's my policy!
だけどご褒美は (Hu! Hu!)
But my reward (Hu! Hu!)
君の笑顔さ (Peace! Peace!)
Is your smile (Peace! Peace!)
いつもそばにいてよね
Always stay by my side,
それだけで元気いっぱい
That alone gives me all my energy!
ついてきてよ後悔させないぜ
Follow me, I won't let you regret it!
ネバギバファイッ！
Never give up fight!
君もそうだね オマツリチーム
You are too, aren't you? Omatsuri team.
ほら (ほら) ほら (ほら)
Look (look) look (look),
限界も 軽々飛び越える
we easily leap over our limits too!
落ち葉に (ネバギバ)
Buried in (Never give up)
埋もれた (ストーリー)
Fallen leaves (Story)
荒らしの日 夢だけを信じて越えてた
I crossed stormy days believing only in my dreams.
頑張って！追いかけて (Hi! Hi!)
Do your best! Keep chasing (Hi! Hi!)
辿り着きたい (Fight! Fight!)
I want to reach (Fight! Fight!)
憧れのステージ
The stage of my dreams.
ココロが跳ね出して困る 抑えきれないよ
My heart leaps out, I can't hold it back!
そしてご褒美は (Hu! Hu!)
And my reward (Hu! Hu!)
君の笑顔さ (Peace! Peace!)
Is your smile (Peace! Peace!)
そのために前を向こう
I'll look forward for that sake.
どんなに深い森も 真っ直ぐいきゃそのうち抜けられる
No matter how deep the forest, go straight and you'll get through.
(むぼ-？) 希望に変えてみます
(Foolish?) I'll try turning it into hope.
(夢の？) また夢が見たいから
(A dream?) Because I want to dream again.
負けない気持ちと
With an unyielding spirit
常夏のスマイルで駆け抜けて
and an endless summer smile, I'll run through!
かっこ悪くても 泥臭くても
Even if it's uncool, even if it's messy,
叶えるまで走り続けよう
I'll keep running until it comes true.
頑張って！頑張って！
Do your best! Do your best!
追いかけて (Hi! Hi!)
Keep chasing (Hi! Hi!)
ほらもう少しだ (Fight! Fight!)
Just a little more (Fight! Fight!)
君と加速したら
If I accelerate with you,
もっとぎゅっと夢を抱きしめに 行こうよ彼方へ
let's go hold our dreams even tighter to the horizon!
だからご褒美は (Hu! Hu!)
So my reward (Hu! Hu!)
君の笑顔さ (Peace! Peace!)
Is your smile (Peace! Peace!)
いつもそばにいてよね
Always stay by my side,
それだけで元気いっぱい ついてきてよ後悔させないぜ
that alone gives me all my energy, follow me!
ネバギバファイッ！
Never give up fight!
はい、まだ帰らないでね！
Hey, don't leave yet!
ライブを最後まで見てくれたそこの君、本当にありがとう！
To you who watched the live all the way to the end, thank you so much!
今からは告知タイム！
Now it's announcement time!
では、いきます！誕生日記念2022ということで、
Now then, here we go! For my 2022 birthday anniversary,
え、今回もありますよ、フルセット！
um, we have it this time too, the full set!
え、記念グッズが4種類！B2タペストリー、ライブロゴタオル、ラバーバンド、キーホルダーということでね、
Um, 4 types of commemorative goods! B2 tapestry, live logo towel, rubber band, and keychain,
え、フルセットの数量限定バージョンもあって、
um, there's also a limited quantity version of the full set,
なんとそちらには、直筆サイン入りのチェキ風ブロマイドカードも付いてくるということでね、お伺いします、売り切れてくださいと、あの願うばかりでございます。
and astonishingly, that comes with an autographed cheki-style bromide card, so um, please, I just pray that it sells out.
はい、そしてですね、
Yes, and also,
まあ、この画像にもなっているまずグッズから見ていこうかなと思います。
well, let's look at the goods shown in this image first.
まず1つ目、こちら、どどん！
First one, here it is, boom!
はい、みなみ
Yes, Minami...
きっぽぽが描き下ろしてくださった、えー、タペストリーでございます。
This is a B2 Tapestry drawn by Kippopo!
ばあ、がわいくない？
Isn't it cute?
めっちゃかわいいでしょ。
Super cute, right?
はい、こちらはですね、えー、普段のまつりちゃん、
So, this one is Matsuri in her usual self—
えー、チアアイドル、チアアイドル？チア部のまつりちゃん。
uh, cheer idol, cheer idol? Cheer club Matsuri.
そして、えー、みんなの前に立つステージでのまつりちゃん。
And Matsuri on stage standing in front of everyone.
そして、普段はみ出ない裏のダンスレッスンで怒られたのかな？
And Matsuri who got scolded during backstage dance practice—
ないちゃお。でもがんばる、そんなまつりちゃん。
Gonna cry. But she does her best, that Matsuri.
んで、配信でよく見るゲームしてるまつりちゃん。
And Matsuri playing games as often seen on stream.
そしてそして、真ん中には今回お披露目した新しい3D衣装でのまつりちゃん。
And in the middle, Matsuri in her newly revealed 3D outfit!
はい、今回はですね、リスタートということで新きって、えー、新しい気持ちで頑張るぞというライブになっておりますので、
Yes, since this time it's 'Re:START', we're starting fresh with a new mindset for the live,
えー、そんな色んなまつりちゃんをね、あの、見ていただけたら嬉しいなと思って、このデザインにしました。
and I wanted you to see all these different sides of Matsuri, so I went with this design.
続いてこちらー！
Moving on to this one!
はい、ライブロゴデザインのタオルでございます。
Yes, this is a towel with the live logo design.
ラギーちゃん、あ、ひらぎ先生ですね(笑)がデザインしてくれました！
Raggy-chan, ah, Hiragi-sensei (laughs) designed it!
リスタートめっちゃかっこいいでしょ。
'Re:START' looks super cool, right?
まつりちゃんがこういうグッズ出すの結構レアでしてね、
It's pretty rare for Matsuri to release goods like this,
あの、まあ、お泊まりしない友達が遊びに来て、洗面所にこれがかかってても、
like, even if a friend who isn't staying over comes to visit and sees this hanging in the bathroom,
なんかかっこいいライブのタオルかなって思われるそんなね、かっちょいいライブタオルです。これめっちゃおすすめです。
they'd think it's a cool live towel. It's super recommended!
はい、続いて、はい、バンドでございますね、
Yes, moving on, we have bands,
ラバーバンド！これまたおしゃれ。
rubber bands! These are also stylish.
ま、これはもうお泊まりしません。
Well, these won't give away any sleepovers.
ま、バレたい人はね、あの、まつりちゃんのキーホルダーも一緒に色々付けていただきたいんですけど、
Well, if you want to be outed, you can attach Matsuri's keyholder along with them,
まあ、これもね、おしゃれでライブといえばこういうバンドつけてね、
but these are also stylish, and speaking of live shows, putting on bands like this...
いや！って感じで盛り上がっていただけたらなって思うので、こちらを買って今日のライブを思い出してください！
and getting hyped up like, 'Yeah!', so buy these and remember today's live!
そして最後に、だどん！
And finally, ta-da!
はい、こちらキーホルダーでございます。
Yes, here is the keyholder.
今回はね、全体的に、なんていうんだろ、まつりちゃんをどんって載せるのは、
This time overall, how should I put it, putting Matsuri front and center...
まあ、おっせみるタペストリーだけで、
...is just for the tapestry you see,
あと外に持っていけるようなものは、あの、ちょっと見る人が見たら分かるって感じのデザインで、
and things you can take outside have a design where people in the know will recognize it,
これめっちゃかわいいでしょ。
Isn't this super cute?
まつりめーっちゃお気に入り今回のごぜ、グッズ全部ね。まあいつものなんだけど。
Matsuri super loves all the merch this time. Well, as always though.
はい、ということで、ま、そんなちょっと、あの、方向性を変えてみたおしゃれなグッズ、ぜひ手に取ってみてください。
So yeah, please check out these stylish goods with a slightly different direction!
ということで、改めて本当に最後までありがとう！絶対買ってくれよな！
With that said, thank you truly to the very end! Make sure you buy them!
ではまた、おまつりわっしょい！大好きだぞ。
See you again, Omatsuri Wasshoi! Love you guys.